<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Public Safety Data</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Public Safety Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Safety Open Data Portal - Part I</title>
      <link>/2017/06/04/public-safety-open-data-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/04/public-safety-open-data-portal/</guid>
      <description>Introduction &amp;amp; Critique Atlanta Boston Part II: 911 Calls New Orleans LA &amp;amp; Los Angeles CA (later this month)   Introduction &amp;amp; Critique The Police Data Initiative website contains data supplied by 135 participating agencies as of today’s date. There is likely an agency near you that you might recognize.
In late 2015, the Tucson Police Department’s Lieutenant Myron “Ron” Holubiak brought the Public Safety Open Data Portal to my attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCR 2014 Available (aka data set 36391)</title>
      <link>/2016/04/03/ucr-2014-available-aka-data-set-36391/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/04/03/ucr-2014-available-aka-data-set-36391/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s common for citizens to be interested in local crime rates either personally or professionally. Most local law enforcement agencies report monthly crime statistics to city officials and/or residents as well as to a state agency. The state then aggregates the data and forwards it to the FBI as part of the Uniform Crime Reporting (UCR) program. The FBI annually releases a report on crime. The most recent was called Crime in the United States 2014 which was released on September 28, 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFIRS 2014 Available</title>
      <link>/2016/03/18/nfirs-2014-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/03/18/nfirs-2014-available/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone.
As a data analyst specializing in public safety for CPSM, I come across National Fire Incident Reporting System (NFIRS) data pretty regularly. Usually, I examine a single fire department at a time, but it&amp;rsquo;s also collected nationally by the Federal Emergency Management Agency.
After it&amp;rsquo;s collected, a portion of the information is provided to interested researchers for review. You request the data and it arrives via US Mail on a CD.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>